That must be it.
あれか…
Step aside!
そこを退け
Inspector Ginoza of CID Division 1...
刑事課一係　宜野座監視官
You are not eligible for access to this information.
該当する情報適格性はありません
You are forbidden to enter this area.
立ち入りを禁じます
What?!
何だと
I'll explain it to you.
説明は私がしよう
Chief...
局長…
I would like to show
Cut open my skull
Look into my head
I don't know why I'm so harsh
I could be so brash
I'm going to clash
'Cause I feel
I can always show my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear, lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all again
'Cause I feel
I can always show my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear, lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all
So it goes again
#18: A Promise
Written on Water
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:死树懒  白心上人    校对:西西     时间轴:葛蔓     压制：娜夏
Please explain to me how Makishima Shougo escaped.
槙島聖護が逃亡に至った経緯をご説明願います
It's very likely that he had help from
someone inside the Ministry of Welfare.
厚生省内部から何らかの手引きがあった可能性が極めて高い
There's no way he could have escaped otherwise.
そうでもなければ逃亡など不可能だからね
We just have to hear what happened directly from Makishima himself.
真相は槙島自身の口から直に聞き出すしか他にない
So when you next apprehend him,
よって再度槙島の身柄を確保するに当たっては
I want your top priority to be bringing him in alive.
その命を脅かさないことに最優先の配慮をしてもらう
I'll be putting Division 1 in charge once again.
改めて君たち一係に任せよう
What on Earth is going on? Please give me a reasonable explanation!
いったいどういうことなんですか
納得のいく説明をしてください
Ginoza...
宜野座君…
Yes?
はい
Not only did you allow Enforcer Kagari to escape,
縢執行官の逃亡を許したのみならず
your investigation into his disappearance has already hit a brick wall.
その捜査すら行き詰まっている状況だ
Now that you have been given the
top priority task of recapturing Makishima,
そこに槙島再逮捕という優先事項が割り込んだことで
you've got the perfect opportunity
to sweep your blunder under the rug.
君は自らの失態を有耶無耶にする絶好のチャンスを得たはずだ
This is my way of showing appreciation
to Division 1 and extending my support.
これは一係への私なりの評価と助け舟…
I hope you appreciate the
consideration I'm showing you as your chief.
その辺の親心を察してもらいたいものだね
But...
Also, I have further orders regarding Enforcer Kougami Shinya.
しかし…
それと　執行官の狡噛慎也
You are to take him off this case
and place him under strict supervision.
あの男は今回の任務から外し　厳重な監視下に置くように…
Why?
どういうことです
Didn't I just tell you? Your top priority is Makishima Shougo's safety.
言ったはずだよ
槙島聖護の身の安全に最優先の配慮をしろと…
As of now, the task of tracking down
Kagari has been transferred to Division 2.
現時点をもって　縢の追跡捜査は二係に委譲
We at Division 1 are in charge of tracking down Makishima Shougo.
我々一係は　槙島聖護の追跡を担当する
Enforcer Kougami, you are to remain within Bureau headquarters.
狡噛執行官は　公安局内に残れ
I want you to work with Analyst Karanomori to back us up.
唐之杜分析官と共に　我々のバックアップを担当してもらう
These are the Chief's orders.
これは局長命令だ
Say...
Don't you think it's a bit strange that
the Chief would order me off the case?
局長命令で俺を外せなんて　妙な話だと思わないか
We're short on manpower as it is, and now she's reducing it further?
ただでさえ足りない人員をさらに削る？
That makes no sense.
あり得んだろう
It suggests that the most important thing here is Makishima's safety,
何より重要なのは槙島の安全で
and that stopping him from committing
more crimes is merely a secondary objective.
やつの再犯を阻止するのは二の次ってことだ
We can't even say we're out to apprehend him, really.
そいつはもう逮捕とは言わない
More like we've been ordered to act as his bodyguards.
身柄の保護…とでも言い直すべきだろう
Our top brass don't intend to judge him.
上の連中は槙島を裁くつもりがない
Even if we manage to apprehend him again,
もし仮に俺たちがまたやつを捕まえてきても
I'm sure the Chief intends to use him for some other purpose.
局長は何か別の目的に利用しようとしている
Am I wrong?
違うか
What are you basing that on?
何を根拠に…
You heard what he said when he called me, didn't you?
やつが俺にかけてきた電話は聞いただろう
He mentioned "the true form of the Sibyl System".
「シビュラシステムの正体」あいつはそう言っていた
He had already discovered the inner
workings that none of us know anything about.
槙島は俺たちでさえ知らない内幕まで辿り着いていたんだ
He was just bluffing!
ただのブラフだ
Do we take criminals at their word now?
犯罪者の言葉を真に受けてどうする
He must have negotiated with someone
who can even control the Sibyl System at will.
誰か…
シビュラシステムさえ意のままに操っている何者かと
槙島は交渉したんだ
In the end, Makishima was able to outwit this person,
そいつは結局槙島に出し抜かれ
but instead of getting angry, they
became even more obsessed with him.
それで怒るどころか　ますます槙島に執着するようになった
Sibyl is a system that is guaranteed to be
independent and free from influence by any organization.
シビュラは　あらゆる機関から独立不干渉を保証されたシステムだ
No one is given that kind of authority.
そんな権限は誰も与えられていない
Makishima probably knows whether that's true or not.
それが事実なのかどうか
おそらく槙島は知っている
They used an aircraft to transport instead of a paddy wagon.
身柄の運搬に護送車ではなく航空機
On top of that, only Drones were on board to guard him.
しかも同乗していたのはドローンのみ
Nothing about this case is normal.
何もかもが異常だ
To start with, whose body was that being taken out from the site?
そもそも現場から運び出された遺体は誰だ
It's been erased from the record, but we clearly saw it.
記録からは消去されているが
俺たちははっきり見たぞ
We all know something's up, Ko.
誰だって納得しちゃいないよ　コウ
But the details are top secret.
The Inspectors wouldn't know the answer, either.
機密区分だ 監視官だって答えは知るまい
You're barking up the wrong tree.
お前は問いただす相手を間違えてる
I guess you're right.
それもそうか…
I'll go grab a bite to eat.
食事してきます
Kougami!
狡噛さん
This is all one big farce. All of it.
全てが茶番だ…何もかも…
After the Senguji Toyohisa case, I took
a look at the report Gino submitted to the top brass.
泉宮寺豊久の事件
あのときギノが上に上げた報告書を見た
Well, I snuck a peek.
こっそりと
Again?
またそんなことを…
The part where the Dominator ignored Makishima was gone without a trace.
ドミネーターが槙島を無視した件は　影も形もなかったよ
From how the report was written,
he was probably forced to delete it.
あの文面じゃ　削らされたってのが実際のところだろうな
シビュラで裁けない人間がいるという事実そのものを
The top brass are trying to erase the very fact
that there are people who can't be judged by Sibyl.
上層部は潰しにかかってる
Well... I guess they don't have much choice.
それは…仕方ないと思います
Don't you feel frustrated?
悔しくないのか
I do. But...
悔しいです　でも…
I came to a realization when the riots broke out the other day.
この間の暴動で改めて思い知りました
I think enforcing justice and
maintaining public order are equally important.
正義の執行も　秩序の維持も　私はどっちも大切だと思います
Then...
なら…
How do you think we can deal with those who are outside the law?
法の外側にいる人間に　何をどうすれば収まりがつくと思う
We have no choice but to make this case
an exception and go back to the old system.
今回ばかりは特例措置で
もう一度昔の制度に立ち戻るしかないでしょう
We prosecute him, open a court,
let him defend himself, and then sentence him.
起訴して法廷を開いて　弁護もさせて
I think that's all we can do.
その上で量刑をするしかないのでは…
That sounds like a pretty daunting process.
気の遠くなる話だな
I wonder how long it'll take to prepare.
お膳立てにどれだけ時間がかかることやら
But there's no other way.
でも　他に方法なんて…
There is, remember?
あっただろ
A quicker way that won't cause anyone trouble.
もっと手っ取り早く　誰の迷惑にもならない方法が…
We should've killed Makishima back then.
あの時…槙島を殺しておけばよかった
But I was wrong to ask you to do it. I'll finish him off myself.
あんたが手を下すのではなく　俺が最後の止めを刺せば…
You're an Inspector, after all. I can't have his blood on your hands.
監視官のあんたに人殺しはさせられない
I'm an Enforcer. I have nothing to lose.
…が　執行官の俺には失うものなんて何もない
That's how our partnership works.
そういうチームワークなんだ
That'll show my worth as a hunting dog, too.
俺だって猟犬の面目躍如さ
That's not enforcing the law.
それは法の執行ではありません
You're just replacing one killer with another.
ただ殺人犯が二人になるだけです
Kougami...
狡噛さん…
You told me once that you wanted to be a detective, not a dog.
いつだったか言ってましたよね
犬ではなく　刑事として働きたいって…
You sure do remember the most trivial things.
どうでもいいことを覚えてんだな
It's not trivial. Completely the opposite.
どうでもよくありません
大切なことです
It's thanks to those words that I didn't quit this job.
あの言葉のおかげで
私　この仕事を辞めずに済みました
Tell me, Kougami.
ねえ　狡噛さん…
Will you always be a detective?
これからもずっと刑事でいてくれますか
Can you promise me that?
そう私に約束してくれますか
Yeah.
ああ…
Oof.
よっと…
So, you think the Chief's throwing us
a ball to play with like the dogs we are?
しかし　まあ
局長は俺たちに犬のようにボール遊びでもやらせてるつもりか
What was I supposed to do?
なあ…
どうすればよかったんだ
What's the right answer in this kind of situation?
こういう時　何が正解なんだ
There's no right answer. All you can do is compromise.
正解はない あるのは妥協だけだ
Hey...
Nobuchika.
伸元
What is it?
何だ…
You need to protect yourself.
身を守れ
Like I said earlier, this is a game of
ball between the master and their dogs.
さっきも言った
こいつはご主人さまと犬のボール遊びだ
If you disobey, you'll just be punished.
逆らえば折檻されるだけ
Given that, you should change your position
to that of a third party, neither dog nor master.
だったら　身の置き所を変えるんだよ
犬でもご主人さまでもない　第三の立場に…
A third party?
第三の
The ball.
ボールだよ
You need to become the ball that's
thrown about, just bouncing and rolling.
ただ投げられて　弾んで転がるだけのボールになりきる
At first glance, it may seem to be beneath you,
一見無様に見えるかもしれんが
but in truth, that's the way to get
hurt least and avoid tiring yourself out.
実は一番傷つかないし 疲れない
It's the wisest course of action, you know.
それが賢い立ち回りってもんだ
I'm sorry to say it, but this case is too much for you to handle.
言っちゃ悪いが この一件はお前の手に余る
Instead of acting rashly and ending up being forced to resign,
下手に動いて詰め腹を切らされるよりも
you're better off acting completely useless as you roll down the slope.
ただ低い方を目指して転がっていくだけの
役立たずに徹する方がいい
That's some pretty terrible advice.
また　ずいぶんとひどいアドバイスがあったもんだ
I thought you'd have more smarts than me about this kind of stuff.
そういう知恵は俺よりもお前の方が回ると思ってたんだがな
I guess that's the so-called wisdom that comes with age.
きっと年の功ってやつだろう
We really can't afford not to have
Kougami when we go after Makishima.
槙島を捕らえる上で　やはり狡噛の戦力は欠かせない
Even if he ends up being a dog that bites his master?
飼い主の手を噛む犬でも　か
When it comes to Makishima-related matters,
こと槙島搦みとなると　狡噛ほど鼻の利く猟犬はいない
there's no other hunting dog with as keen a nose as Kougami's.
That detective instinct that you so often talk about...
あんたがよく口にする　「刑事の勘」
It's a talent that I don't happen to have after all.
結局　俺が持ち合わせることのなかった才能だ
But the Chief ordered you to take him off the case, right?
だが任務から外せというのは局長命令だろ
Once we can get him out of the cage, the game is ours.
檻の外にさえ出してしまえばこっちのもんだ
The only remaining question is:
what excuse shall I come up with?
後は　どういう口実を捏ち上げるかだが…
It's not like you to come up with such a radical idea, Ginoza.
宜野座君にしては
またずいぶんと思い切った手を考えたわよね
I'm sorry to ask you to take part in something risky like this.
申し訳ない
危ない綱渡りなのに 片棒を担がせてしまって
That's okay.
いいわよ
I agree that the way Kagari from
your division disappeared is suspicious,
そっちの縢君の消え方がうさんくさいってのは私も同意見
and that we can't let Makishima Shougo run free.
それに槙島聖護を放っておけないっていうのもね
We already have two people absent from the CID as it is.
現在 刑事課全体で執行官に２人の欠員が出ている
Given the present situation, we can't let you waste time sitting around in the lab.
この状況でお前にラボで油を売らせておくわけにもいかない
So I asked Inspector Aoyanagi in Division 2 to temporarily
have you and one of her Enforcers switch places, and she agreed.
そこでだ 二係の青柳監視官と相談し
一時的な執行官の交代に応じてもらった
Go to Division 2 for a while, and help them search for Kagari Shuusei.
狡噛は当面二係で縢秀星の捜索を手伝え
We'll borrow one of the Division 2 people in your place.
代わりにわれわれも二係から人員を１人借り受ける
When we have so few leads on Kagari's case as it is,
縢君の件 これだけ手掛かりが少ないと
it's understandable that the investigation
would follow a somewhat roundabout course.
捜査が迷走するのも仕方ないわ
Kougami, whatever you do, don't pull any stupid stunts.
狡噛君 くれぐれも余計なまねはしないでね
At least not while I'm looking, anyway.
私の目に付く範囲では
Yes, ma'am.
承知してます
This is a special circumstance as defined in Code K32.
コードＫ３２に基づく特殊事例です
We will be taking Kougami Shinya into custody.
狡噛慎也執行官の身柄を拘束します
Wha—
Tsk.
なっ…
If you really thought that you could outwit me with such a cheeky trick,
こんな小ざかしい計略で出し抜けると思ったなら
you must really take me for quite the fool.
なめられたものだな 私も
I'm surprised to see you're such a big fan of mine, Chief Kasei.
あんたがそこまで熱烈な俺のファンだったとは意外だよ
禾生局長
And I'm surprised that you think you're in any position to talk back.
ここで減らず口をたたける君の精神構造はまったくもって
It's really quite hard to grasp.
理解に苦しむな
Chief!
局長 説明させてください　これは…
Please let me explain! This is—
That won't be necessary.
いいや　説明には及ばない
Ginoza, isn't this the sort of situation where
the more you talk, the deeper you dig yourself?
宜野座君　ここは口を開くほど墓穴を掘る局面ではないかね
Making judgments based on your
personal discretion isn't always a bad thing.
個人の裁量による判断も必ずしもとがめるべきものとは限らない
What's important is to produce a satisfying result.
要は満足いく結果さえ伴えばいいのだ
In the end, that's the sole basis for evaluation.
評価の基準はそれだけだ
That's precisely why it's important to know
when to quit when you take a risky gamble.
だからこそ危険な賭けに打って出る際は
引き際の判断が重要になる
The question is how quickly and firmly
you can close the books on your failure.
自らの不始末をどれだけ速やかに
断固たる態度で清算できるか…
Now, Inspector Ginoza...
さて　宜野座監視官
An Enforcer under your supervision is
about to commit a serious breach of trust.
君の監視下にある執行官が今重大な背任を犯そうとしているわけだが
How do you intend to deal with this situation?
この場面にどう対処する
Instead of just going on and on with foolish explanations,
愚にもつかない弁明をただ並べ立てるより
are you able to demonstrate you can act clearly and decisively?
もっと明晰で非の打ち所のない決断力を示すことはできるかな
Crime Coefficient is 265.
「犯罪係数　２６５」
An Enforcer registered at the Criminal Investigation Department.
「刑事課登録執行官 任意執行対象です」
This target has Enforce At Will status.
The safety will be released.
Good. An acceptable demonstration of your own worth.
うん　結構…
君は順当に自らの有用性を証明している
However, your lenient manner still leaves much to be desired.
だが　詰めの甘さも否めない
Enforcement mode is Non-Lethal... Para...
「執行モード ノンリーサル·パラライ…」
Lethal... Eliminate...
Now, Ginoza. Show me how you take charge as a leader.
さあ　宜野座君 君の責任者としての采配を…
Show me that you can act decisively, unhindered by emotion.
情に流されない決断力を私に見せてくれないか
For a target whose Crime Coefficient is under 300,
犯罪係数３００以下の対象にはパラライザーモードが適用されます
Paralyzer mode should be used.
Inspector Ginoza, that Dominator appears to be faulty.
宜野座さん　そのドミネーター故障してますよ
You should send it in for maintenance immediately.
すぐメンテナンスに出さないと
Yeah.
Akane—
朱ちゃ…
You should be grateful to Akane.
朱ちゃんに感謝しなさいよ
She avoided your spine and shot you in the leg instead.
中枢神経避けて足に当ててくれたんだから
Seems like she's gotten used to handling the Dominator, huh?
もうドミネーターの扱いも慣れたもんか
You know,
何かさ～
when an inexperienced newbie rapidly becomes tough,
初々しい新人がどんどんタフになっちゃうのって
on one hand it's reassuring, but it's also a bit sad. Complicated, isn't it?
頼もしいような寂しいような…
複雑なもんね
She'll get tougher and tougher.
あいつはこれからもっともっとタフになるさ
I've got a question.
１個質問
Sure. What is it?
はーい　何でしょう
Does that helmet still work?
あのヘルメットまだ使えるのか
More or less. But when the Sibyl System is
completely restored, they plan on installing countermeasures.
一応ね
でもシビュラシステムの完全復旧と共に 対策プログラムが実装される予定
After that, it'll just be a regular helmet.
そうなったらあとはもう普通のヘルメット
How long until it's restored?
完全復旧まで
Six more days.
あと６日
Are you going to take a piece of evidence with you?
証拠品持ってくつもり
I need it for the investigation.
捜査のために必要なんだよ
This from the guy who got taken off the case?
捜査からは外されてるくせに
Have they notified you guys of that, too?
こっちにも通達は来てるのか
Hmm... Who knows?
ん～どうだったっけ
Come to think of it, maybe I haven't heard yet.
そういやまだ聞いてなかったかも
Whatever you do, don't take it outside, okay?
絶対に外に持ち出さないでよね
I know.
分かってるよ
Say, Shinya...
ねえ　慎也君ん
I was thinking... Should I have slept with you at least once?
私さ～せめて一度ぐらいはあなたと寝てみるべきだったのかな
Who knows? I don't think we're each other's type, though.
どうだかな…
お互い趣味じゃなかったと思うぜ
I guess you're right.
ん…そうだよね
Oh, the helmet, huh? I forgot you could use that.
ああ　ヘルメットね～
その手があったか
This is to celebrate your discharge
from the hospital. Here, have some.
退院祝いだ　まあ飲めよ
I've been looking at the info on Makishima that you collected.
お前の集めた槙島の資料見せてもらってるぜ
It looks messy at first glance, but it's actually quite organized.
一見とっちらかっているようでいて
きっちり整理がついてる
It's prepared in such a way that you can take
just the important parts, when push comes to shove.
いざとなれば 肝心な部分だけいつでも持ち出せる構えだな
Why are you so obsessed with Makishima?
なぜそこまでやつにこだわる
Is it evil that you can't tolerate? Or is it Makishima himself?
お前が許せないのは悪か それとも槙島自身か
Neither one, pops.
どっちも違うよ　とっつぁん
If I give up now,
今ここで諦めても
eventually I'll come to resent myself
for letting Makishima Shougo get away.
いずれ俺は槙島聖護を見逃した自分を許せなくなる
I could never allow that to happen.
そんなのは真っ平だ
That answer suits you perfectly, Ko.
お前らしい答えだな　コウ
This is from back when I worked for the Metropolitan Police Department.
警視庁時代の思い出だ
I once prepared a safe house for use in emergencies.
いざというときに備えてセーフハウスを用意してたことがある
It might be of use to you too.
何かの役に立つかもしれん
Pops...
とっつぁん…
Are you gonna leave without saying a word to the young lady?
お嬢ちゃんには黙ったまま行くのか
I can't face her now.
いまさら合わせる顔がない
At least help her come to terms with it.
せめて気持ちの整理だけはつけさせてやれよ
Yeah...
そうだな…
There's no way I could love anyone,
Dareka wo aisuru koto nante
Dekiru wake nakutte
But I wish to be loved by someone in turn
The world may not have
Dakedo dareka ni aisaretakute
Ended yesterday after all,
Kawaranai kinou ga zutto tsuzuita to shite mo
But we will not budge
Doko ni mo ike ya shinainda
watashi to kimi
From where we are
Kamisama doko he itte shimatta no nee
God, in favor of which parts have you left us?
Henji wa nakute itsu datte sou da yo
I receive no reply, I never do
I'm sorry. I couldn't keep my promise.
「すまない…俺は約束を守れなかった」
I wanted to go into a line of work where I could protect people.
「誰かを守る役目を果たしたい」
That's why I became a detective.
「そう思って俺は刑事になった」
But Makishima changed everything.
「だが槙島の存在が全てを変えた」
That man will continue to kill people.
「あの男はこれからも人をあやめ続けるだろう」
And yet, the law can't judge him.
「なのに法律ではやつを裁けない」
As long as I'm a detective, I can't touch him.
「俺は刑事でいるかぎりあの男に手出しができない」
This case made me aware...
「今度の一件で思い知った」
that the law can't protect people.
「法律で人は守れない」
In that case, my only option is to step outside the law.
「なら　法の外に出るしかない」
Tsunemori Akane... There is no
doubt that your way of living is correct.
「常守朱…あんたの生き方は間違いなく正しい」
Don't lose sight of that just because I betrayed you.
「俺に裏切られたからってそこを見失ってはいけない」
I chose a different path solely in order to have my own way.
「俺はあくまで身勝手に 自分の意地を通すためだけに
あんたと違う道を選んだ」
I'm aware that this is the wrong thing to do.
「これが過ちだと理解はしている」
But I know that I can only come to terms
with my old self by taking the wrong path.
「だが　俺はきっと間違った道を進むことでしか
今までの自分と折り合いがつけられない」
I won't ask you to forgive me.
「許してくれ…とは言わない」
The next time we meet, you'll be in a position to judge me.
「次に会うときはおそらく
あんたは俺を裁く立場にいるだろう」
When that time comes, please fulfill your duty with no mercy.
「そのときは容赦なく務めを果たせ」
Don't turn your back on your beliefs.
「信念に背を向けてはいけない」
Although it was only for a short time,
「ほんのいっときだったが あんたの下で働けて幸いだった」
I feel fortunate that I was able to work under you.
Thank you.
「礼を言う…」
You idiot...
バカ…
You'll never walk alone
I walk with you
Anata to iku
Donna tsumi mo
I will share all your sins
Seotte ageru
Together with you
Michi naki michi wo
Aruiteku no
I walk
A trackless path
Anata to futari de
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all individuals and organizations that appear
in this show are fictitious and any similarity to those in existence in the real world is purely coincidental.
This is a world where the mental state and
personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed,
these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are
commonly called "Psycho-Pass".
This is a world where the mental state and
personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed,
these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are
commonly called "Psycho-Pass".